Who is this?
His name is Suroso.
The Chief of Karang Setan Village.
What do you want to do with him?
I want him to die quickly.
Why should he die?
So I can replace him and become
the Chief of Karang Setan.
Are you ready to bear the sins?
If I wasn't ready,
I wouldn't have come here to meet you.
Pardi.
I took half to pay your debt.
Daliman
Why are you lining up, huh?
Your wages are gone
from paying your the debt!
Please, Mr. Banteng.
Please take half for now.
I need the money.
Thank you.
Please don't.
Let's teach him a lesson.
-Soak him.
-No!
-Please.
-Keep going.
Don't lie to me.
I swear.
I have nothing left to pay my debt.
Boss.
I beg you, Boss.
I shall accept Mr. Kawi's request.
I'll let my daughter work here
to pay my debt.
DANGDUT NIGHT CLUB
I know, right?
I came here, and her you are.
I'm Lawu.
-Here.
-Dad…
It's okay.
Sir, please don't.
Please, don't.
Help! Help me!
Please help!
-Sweetie?
-Dad!
-Sweetheart!
-Help!
-My daughter!
-Sweetheart!
-Dad!
KARANG SETAN VILLAGE HEAD OFFICE
It won't start?
Yes.
May I help you?
Sure.
You rarely use it, do you?
Very rarely.
Usually my father drives it.
Thank God.
-Thank you, sir.
-You're welcome.
Sorry to trouble you.
Not a problem.
It would be a problem
if I had to pry open the engine.
Is the office open or closed,
why is it so quiet?
It's open.
But the Chief isn't there.
He passed away two weeks ago.
May he rest in peace.
Thank you.
Peace be upon you.
And upon you too.
I want to find someone
who used to live here.
-Who is it?
-His name is Kasman Wironegoro.
Kasman?
Gun, do you know him?
He lived here quite a long time ago.
I was still a little boy.
Listen. We'll help you
search for him in the district.
Just come again later.
Sorry. What's your name?
I'm Pramuja.
Oh, you can fill this form.
Sorry to trouble you.
Not a problem.
It would be a problem
if I had to pry open the engine.
-Suzzanna?
-Yes?
-Who is it from?
From Bisman?
Mom?
Hey.
Mom!
Why did you accept it?
It doesn't feel right
if we keep refusing Bisman's gift.
That's what he wants.
He waits until we feel uncomfortable.
After a while,
we'll end up accepting his proposal.
Don't you feel sorry for our daughter?
She's becoming an old virgin.
I also want Suzzanna
to get a husband soon.
But not with a man who already has a wife.
Especially that man named Bisman.
Gosh, honey.
Suzzanna will not be miserable.
Even if she becomes a second wife.
Because Bisman's wealth
will never run out.
Oh, dear God.
Do you know how he got that wealth?
In what way?
We don't need to worry about
other people's lives.
What's important is that we're nice,
and our daughter is safe.
Oh, so that's what you think?
Sweetie, do you want to
accept Bisman's proposal?
No, Dad.
Why not?
Your mother said
Bisman's wealth
will never run out for generations.
It's not that I don't want
to get married soon, Mom.
But I want to find a good husband.
That's right.
A good husband… When will you find one?
We'll meet soon.
I can feel it. My soulmate is near.
Such a know-it-all.
What is going on?
The situation is getting worse, Teacher.
Come in, come in.
I'm sorry.
I invited my friends here
hoping that you can find a way out.
You all know that I am a nobody.
I'm just a teacher.
But in my opinion,
Mr. Satrio is more than just a teacher.
Because only you have the courage
to go against Bisman's men.
If that time you did not appear,
I would have been dead.
Teacher. Do you have a death wish?
You guys have a death wish
if you still insist on disturbing
the sellers here.
You bastard.
Look.
Everyone, look.
There are only four of them.
There is no reason to be afraid.
Anyone can do the same thing I did
when faced with a situation like that.
But most people just run away, sir.
Mr. Satrio,
now is not the time to be humble.
The residents here
want you to lead the resistance
against Bisman.
Not by violence,
but in ways that do not break the law.
What do you mean?
You must run for office,
in the village head elections next month,
replacing the late Chief Suroso.
Because if not,
Bisman will become the sole candidate.
And that's exactly what he wants.
Listen, you can't act like a hero, Dad.
I am not.
These days, everyone
should want to be a hero.
The behavior of Bisman
and his men is truly barbaric.
And no one should let it happen.
Including me.
But people expect you to step
forward to lead the resistance.
I'm thinking about it.
Dad, just mind your own business.
If needed, we should just move
to another village.
Sweetheart.
We must fight injustice.
Imagine, what if it happened to our
family? Aren't you going to ask for help?
Does it have to be you
who steps forward to lead?
Whoever becomes the leader,
everyone must be ready to accept the fact
that every change will demand sacrifice.
Do you understand?
You're right.
But don't hurt your own family.
I will never.
Not directly.
But because of your actions,
Bisman might get angry.
He'll make our family miserable.
What is the difference?
Whatever.
Are you sure Satrio dares
to lead people against me?
From what I heard, their conversation
was heading in that direction, Boss.
What's so great about him?
Is he really a hero?
Maybe because
he had the guts to fight back.
Against who?
-Me and the guys.
-He defeated you guys?
That time it didn't turn into a fight,
but he has the influence.
Making people angry and willing to fight.
That bastard is the source of the problem.
Of all the villagers of Karang Setan,
he's the only one
who didn't want to sell his land to us.
There's one more thing, Boss.
something Satrio is planning
that I believe is extremely dangerous.
Preventing Bisman
from becoming chief is necessary.
But if he has already committed acts
of oppression against you
and ordered his men
to carry out violence against you,
why is it that until now no one
has ever reported this to the police?
We've done that before.
But it was ignored.
Could it be because the ones who came
were small people like me?
If that's the case,
then we should ask you for help as well.
Please go to the city
and file a report with the police.
He's confident
that the police will
shut this place down permanently.
A night of terror.
Curses come from all directions.
Tormented souls, full of suspicion.
A body consumed by dark forest spirits.
Come from the north,
south, west, and east.
Come to me on this darkest night.
I am your servant, I am your offering.
I give you my blood and my life.
Drink.
I planted it
at the back door of his house.
It is called
the death-strike curse.
Mom, what's wrong?
Mom, Kitty is dead!
Kitty?
Hot! Hot! Oh, it's hot!
Hot!
-It's hot!
-What's wrong?
Hot!
What happened to you?
Ouch, it's hot, ouch!
Hot, hot!
-It's hot!
-What is happening?
Hot, hot!
Honey, what's wrong?
Dad?
Hot, it hurts, hot!
-It hurts.
-Dad!
Stay away, dear, this must be witchcraft.
-Witchcraft?
-Hot! It's hot.
Wait…
-What is this?
-Father!
Ouch, it hurts!
It hurts, what's happening to me?
-Dad…
-Help me!
Ouch, it hurts!
Ouch, ouch!
-Ouch!
-Dad!
-Honey!
-Honey?
-Dad?
-Dad!
-Honey…
Honey…
Long live Chief Bisman!
Long live!
DANGDUT NIGHT CLUB
Boss, wait! Calm down.
Boss.
Here you go, Boss.
I had to look for it in your room.
I couldn't find it at the front desk.
Why didn't you ask my wife?
Mrs. Suroh is not here.
The maid said, she just left
for the prayers at Suzzanna's house.
What?
Go after her. Stop her.
-Don't let her meet Suzzanna.
-Yes.
She's going to babble
all sorts of things about Satrio's death.
Yes, Boss.
Don't go alone.
It must be crowded there.
If you meet people who don't like us,
it'll be a hassle.
-Take Banteng and Lawu with you.
-Yes, Boss.
Where is your mother?
She went to the mosque.
Delivering food to the orphans.
Alright then. I'll just speak with you.
So that my heart can be at peace.
Because even in the afterlife,
I would feel haunted by guilt
if I helped keep secret
the injustice that you deserve to know.
What injustice, Ma'am?
The cause of your father's death.
Back then,
he sent a dark spell to Chief Suroso.
Until he got sick and died.
Oh, dear God.
After that,
the people held an election.
And he had to go up against your father
who was liked by many people.
Your father's fate, my dear,
was not much different from Suroso.
Killed by witchcraft.
Oh, God.
-Mrs. Suroh.
-What do you want?
Sorry, ma'am, Boss is looking for you.
Earlier, he told us
to look for you and bring you home.
Tell your boss, okay?
I'm staying here.
Well, if you want to stay here, please do.
But we will also stay here
and wait for you.
No need! You should go!
Banteng!
No need to make it difficult.
We're just carrying out orders.
Let's go home.
-Come!
-What the heck?
-Come home!
-How dare you!
You're so rude!
How dare you touch someone else's wife?
Why are you so angry?
No wonder Boss wants to get married again.
Banteng!
How dare you!
-Where do you think you're going?
-Let me go!
Idiot!
Mrs. Suroh…
You.
If you ever tell our boss, you're dead!
Come on, come on!
Where are you going now?
Go on, jump!
Jump!
Boss.
I am ready to accept the punishment.
Even if you'll kill me,
I am willing…
What about Suzzanna?
-Suzzanna…
-After seeing Mrs. Suroh's condition,
Suzzanna got scared
and ran out of the house.
We tried to catch up,
but we lost her.
We tried to find her.
But we decided
to return to Suzzanna's house.
To take care of Mrs. Suroh's body.
Does she know
that I put a spell on her father?
It seems like…
Mrs. Suroh hadn't told her yet, Boss.
Find Suzzanna.
As soon as you do, report to me.
Don't let anything happen to Suzzanna.
Yes, Boss.
Bruised and battered.
It's cracked. There is a deep wound here.
She got stabbed too.
But she's not dead yet.
Pramuja.
Stay until she gets better, okay?
Poor thing.
I can heal her internal wounds.
You heal the outside wounds.
Yes, Auntie.
Her will to live is strong.
Pramuja?
What you said is true.
It took three weeks for her to wake up.
Don't get up yet.
Your bones are not strong enough.
Rest.
Where am I?
In my house.
Kalinegoro Village.
This is my nephew, Pramuja.
It was my nephew who helped you.
What's your name, dear?
Suzzanna.
My name is Gayatri.
And I'm Bawuk.
Take it easy.
Are your legs strong enough?
Thanks to you and your aunt.
-Can I help you?
-No need.
I'll manage. Have a seat.
Maybe you don't remember
but we have met before.
Let me help you.
I remember.
Her hand still hurts, Auntie.
I'm helping her.
Yes, go ahead and help her.
TWO WEEKS LATER
-I'm getting the clothes.
-I'll do it.
A moment.
He has hurt me for decades, Ma'am.
I can't take it anymore.
He even started beating up my kids.
I can't let this go on any longer.
How can I help you?
Please send my husband home, Ma'am.
Send him home?
What do you mean?
Return him to God.
Pramuja.
-What is this, Auntie?
-I already told you.
Never come in here.
All this time I thought
that you only practiced healing.
But this, this is all…
-Are you disappointed?
-I…
Then you'd better go.
-And don't stay here anymore.
-But…
Please forgive my mistake
and impudence, Ma'am.
But she forced her way in.
What do you want?
Let me learn from you, Ma'am.
So that I can get revenge
on the cruel people who did this to me.
My dear.
Aren't you afraid of God?
Why do you ask that?
Oh, dear.
I know what you want.
I also know that, once you start learning,
you have to be ready
to go to the depths of hell.
For me,
the fire of hell
is in Karang Setan, Ma'am.
And I…
will try with
the strength that I have left
to put it out, Ma'am.
Even if I get burned in the process.
Do you really want it that desperately?
I don't know where else
to ask for help, Ma'am.
I have to save my mom.
Come then, dear.
For a long time,
I've been looking for someone
who I consider worthy
to inherit my knowledge.
I thought Pramuja would do it.
But it turned out he only wanted
to study healing.
For him, things like this
are polytheism.
And then you came.
My inner eye can immediately see
that you have the ability
which will make it easier for you
to absorb the knowledge I have.
What abilities, Ma'am?
Do you see Bawuk?
Yes.
Have you ever seen
Pramuja talking to Bawuk?
Pramuja can't see Bawuk.
But you can.
Bawuk is actually a Jinn
who lives in this house.
You were unconscious for almost a month.
It seems to have honed your skills.
And with this ability,
I'm sure, my dear,
that you will easily learn
the knowledge that I possess.
First of all,
you have to undergo white fasting.
For seven days and seven nights.
And during that time,
you have to stay standing.
You must not sleep.
After fasting, you have to soak in water
on the coast of the South Sea
while continuously praying.
So that you are ready to receive
the knowledge you desire.
And what requires the most strength
and endurance of your body and soul is
meditating for 40 days
and 40 nights.
At one point,
you will find a spirit familiar
who is compatible with you.
Who will always be ready to help you.
And carry out all
your orders and requests.
As long as
you give her offerings
according to her wishes.
Keep your heirloom and take it with you,
wherever you go.
Because that's where
your familiar spirit will stay
until you need its help.
Good afternoon, Chief.
Good afternoon.
How can I help?
Listen, Chief, the reason why I came here
is to find out about someone
who once lived here.
His name is Kasman Wironegoro.
You're looking for someone named Kasman?
What's the reason?
He is my father.
I don't have any pictures,
but I have a picture of my mother.
Your father was a savage.
He once got a woman pregnant
and then got kicked out of this village.
I'm sorry, Chief.
But do you know where my father is?
Or at least where he lives?
Your father is dead.
-Is this coffee or horse piss?
-Coffee, Boss.
Don't talk back to me!
I should go.
Who made coffee for the chief?
I did.
Was that coffee or horse piss?
Coffee, obviously.
Make a better one.
The Chief left already.
Just make some more.
For me, Tohir, and Diran.
Gosh.
Geez.
When morons get promoted as officials,
they get so cocky.
Idiots.
What are you using that for?
Herbal drink.
Here, I've made more coffee.
What did you add to this coffee?
Well, I had some nutmeg powder,
I tried mixing it in.
Now, this is coffee!
Try some, Tohir.
Extraordinary!
Give it a try, Diran.
Why does it taste like horse piss?
You don't understand coffee.
Give it to me.
Make me a cup again tomorrow, okay?
Yes, sir.
WELCOME TO KARANG SETAN VILLAGE
Mom?
Mom.
Mom, you're burning up.
It's been a long time, sweetie.
Sometimes I get a fever,
sometimes it goes away.
What happened to your face?
After you
went missing…
The three thugs, Bisman's men
come almost every day.
I even memorized their names.
Banteng, Lawu, Kawi.
They come in
the morning asking for breakfast.
They come in the afternoon, and at night
while they got drunk.
If they don't like my cooking,
they get angry.
Those savages.
They must be punished
as severely as possible.
We're no match
for their power.
My dear…
You should leave this village.
Sweetie.
I can't take it anymore.
Remember, sweetie.
Please bury me
beside your father.
Mom…
SUTINI DAUGHTER OF PRAYITNO
I'm sorry for your loss.
Suzzanna?
Why are you here?
I…
I'm looking for my father's gravestone.
I've heard that there is a possibility
that my father has died.
My mother passed away.
Indeed, to Allah we belong
and to Him we shall return.
Suzzanna. I'm sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
If you…
ever need my help,
you can meet me at the mosque.
It's nearby.
I'm staying there for now.
Thank you, Pramuja.
Hang in there.
Suzzanna.
It's so unfortunate that we keep meeting
in sad situations like this.
The people of
the Karang Setan village administration,
offer our deepest condolences
on the passing of Mrs. Sutini.
Thank you, Boss.
Please don't call me that.
You can call me Chief. Or Bisman.
Thank you, Bisman.
Where have you been, Suzzanna?
Since your father passed away,
you just disappeared.
Let me propose to you, Suzzanna.
I will only accept your proposal
after my mind is completely calm.
And my heart can only be at peace
after I know for sure
who put a spell on my father.
Can you catch that person,
and bring him before
me in a helpless state?
My heart shall be at peace
once you punish your three men,
who had the heart to oppress my mother
until she got sick and died.
They are also the ones
who had been chasing me
until I fell off a cliff.
I was unconscious for a month.
If you can sort it all out,
I will accept your proposal.
The boss will definitely tell Lesus
to put a spell on the three of us.
Impossible.
Boss Bisman is like a brother to us.
Brothers don't put spells on each other.
What do you mean brothers?
Whenever Boss Bisman says we're brothers,
he never means it.
So that we feel close to him.
Loyal to him.
We're not actually brothers!
-Is that so?
-You idiot!
Back when we were porters,
Boss Bisman was already rich.
If he doesn't like us anymore,
it's easy for him to get rid of us.
So…
What should we do?
The source of the problem is Suzzanna.
Suzzanna has poisoned the boss's mind.
If the poison dies,
the boss will come to his senses again.
So we have to kill Suzzanna first.
-Before he finishes us off.
-Hey!
Why are you acting
like a fool just like Lawu?
Better to be a fool but act on it!
Than being smart but cowardly.
If you don't have the guts,
I can go alone!
Huh? Hey, hey.
Hey!
Hey, my car!
Boss.
I can't take it anymore.
I'd rather die, Boss.
Nonsense. You must be strong.
I swear to God.
I can't take it.
Please kill me.
Please…
Kill me, Boss.
Please kill me.
Please.
Kill me, Boss.
Kill me, please.
Please…
Forgive me, Banteng.
Just do it.
Boss!
I know what's on your mind.
I swear to God.
I had absolutely no intention
of killing Banteng.
I can't bear
to see him suffering for so long.
Keep God's name out of your mouth, Boss.
God won't even care
that you keep mentioning Him.
As if you practice religion.
Pramuja.
Good evening.
I'm here to give you some food.
I know that you're grieving.
I figured you haven't eaten.
Thank you for the food.
Please come in.
So, Pramuja.
Have you found your father?
It seems like the chief knows
something about my father.
But he's still covering it up.
So when are you going home?
I'm staying here for now.
I want to find out what Bisman is hiding.
You should stay away from Bisman.
He is dangerous.
He killed my father.
I'll just…
expose his rottenness and help you.
I don't need help.
I don't want anything bad
to happen to you. I don't want you…
I don't want to lose someone
who has been good to me.
Don't be afraid.
I have no fear anymore.
Don't stay here too long.
You are not safe.
They killed your family.
I'll have my revenge on all of them.
In what way?
You are alone, Suzzanna.
You could be the next victim.
Oppression demands rebellion.
If that means I will become a victim,
let it be.
-Suzzanna, you…
-It's getting late.
I… I should go.
Do not forget to eat.
Yesterday a Quran teacher came here.
Saying you were the one
who requested a teacher for me.
Are you mocking me?
Quran teacher? What's his name?
Lastri or something?
A woman?
-Where is she from?
-From Karang Setan, she said.
What does she look like?
Why are you so curious?
-Is she your girlfriend?
-Nonsense.
Just admit it.
If you have no relationship with her,
why would she ask for your photo?
She asked for a photo?
And you gave it to her?
Hey, why are you daydreaming?
You might get possessed.
My beloved children.
Come over.
Tell the man to climb up the coconut tree.
Honey? Who asked for coconuts?
Oh my God, honey!
Honey!
Lawu!
Help!
Boss.
It turns out
for the sake of a woman,
you can so easily sacrifice your own men.
Last week, Banteng died.
Now, look at Lawu.
It's true that I'm mad at you guys.
But I would never
cast spells on my own men.
Hey!
Where are you going?
Come on!
Make him come out!
Lesus!
Come out!
Attack! Burn!
Burn everything!
Come on!
He must have a protective spell.
What do you mean?
Try cutting off his big toe.
That's usually their weakness.
Go get him.
-Come on.
-Hey!
Hold him!
Kneel down.
Stab him!
Stab him.
Burn him.
-Come on!
-Burn!
Throw everything in!
Burn!
Hey, here.
Burn him!
-Let's go home!
-Let's go!
Boss?
What is it, Kawi?
Don't worry.
I'm not here to mess around.
I'm relieved because
you can't possibly cast any spells
on me and Lawu anymore.
Your favorite shaman,
has become a corpse.
You stupid son of a bitch!
Why kill him?
I've said it many times
that I never ordered anyone
to finish you off!
I'm already confused, Kawi!
Now I'm even more confused!
Honey?
Lawu?
Wu. Lawu!
Nurse!
Look! Do you really think that Lesus
can still send spells?
Lawu!
Honey!
Lawu, wake up honey!
Peace be upon you.
And upon you too. Can I help you?
I want to meet the chief.
Please wait.
Have a seat.
Thank you.
So…
Who actually cast spells
on Banteng and Lawu?
Sorry, Boss.
I still don't know who did it.
But, whoever he is,
I think, he acted on Suzzanna's request.
Why do you think so?
Do you think
there's anyone else who has a grudge
against us more than her?
Kliwon! Tohir! Diran!
-Yes!
-Yes, Boss!
Yes, Boss?
Starting today, you three
keep an eye on Suzzanna 24 hours a day.
If you see her entertaining guests,
or if there is someone suspicious,
report to me immediately.
That person might be the shaman.
Or his men that Suzzanna hired.
-Understood?
-Understood, Boss.
If you can tell me who the shaman is,
I will triple your salary.
So, keep your eyes open.
Hey, you!
What are you doing there?
I…
I want to ask about my father.
Do you have time?
-What's your name again?
-Pramuja.
I told you, your father is dead.
So, I'm sorry.
There's nothing I can do.
Remember, open your eyes.
We have to keep looking for the shaman.
For triple salary, I'd even meet a ghost.
But this is a dark shaman.
What do you mean?
Well, if it's a ghost, we can run away.
But if it's a shaman,
wherever we go, his spells will follow us.
You're right.
Gosh.
I'm scared now.
Besides, how are we supposed to know
if a person is a black magic shaman?
My grandmother said,
black magic shamans usually
own a keris and a voodoo doll.
Whoever owns those items
must be the black magic shaman.
I'm getting more and more scared.
Me too.
Tohir, come here.
You and I, check over there, okay?
Diran, you check over there.
Why am I alone?
No need to be afraid like that.
Come on, Tohir.
Tohir? Kliwon?
Geez.
Suzzanna.
-Why are you still here?
-I need to tell you something.
I met Bisman earlier,
and I heard his men think
that you hired a black magic shaman
to put a spell on them.
Now, they have sent people to spy on you.
We have to get out of here immediately.
You are not safe alone.
I cannot leave, Pramuja.
What are you thinking, Suzzanna?
You can't fight them alone.
They're crazy for thinking
that you cast a spell on them.
You don't understand.
You better go.
We'll meet again after everything is done.
I don't understand what you are thinking.
A crow?
Why did you have to learn things like this
from Aunt Gayatri?
This is the only way.
The only way for whom?
For people who don't
believe in the power of God?
You're not that kind of person, Suzzanna.
Not everyone is as unfortunate as I am.
And not everyone who suffers misfortune
chooses this path.
What kind of path do
you think I should take?
Pray?
And continue to pray for God's protection?
Suzzanna.
For years I prayed
to Him with all my heart.
Believing that He exists.
Believing in His strength and power.
That He will always protect me.
And protect the people I love.
My father.
My mother.
But then what?
When evil people killed my father,
and oppressed my mother…
Did God help me?
No.
-Suzzanna, you…
-Miss Suzzanna?
What's wrong?
I thought I heard a man's voice.
Is there anyone else here?
There's no one else here.
If you want, please see for yourself.
Yes.
Excuse me.
What's wrong?
What you said is true, Miss.
There's no one else here.
Sit down, I'll make you a drink.
No thank you, I'm full.
Gosh.
Kliwon!
Sorry, Tohir! Sorry, sorry.
Kliwon? Tohir!
Danger. Danger!
Ghost!
-Ghost…
-This is Tohir, not a ghost!
I know who the black magic shaman is.
-Really?
-Who?
Let's just report it to the boss,
shall we?
Hey, Diran, wait!
You're not the only one
who wants a raise! Hey!
He figured it out.
He will report to Bisman soon.
Don't you worry.
He won't be able to tell anyone.
I'm not as nice as you think.
You better go.
Leave, Pramuja.
I have no business with you guys.
DANGDUT NIGHT CLUB
What were you doing at Suzzanna's house?
Protecting her from people like you.
Who's protecting who?
You can't even protect yourself.
I am in charge here.
And I will destroy
whoever goes against me.
I am not afraid of people like you.
What happened?
I got pushed by Kliwon, Boss.
What are you doing here?
Aren't you supposed
to be watching Suzzanna's house?
I have important news, Boss.
-You definitely won't believe it.
-What news?
I know who the black magic shaman is.
Who is it?
The black magic shaman is…
Don't mess with me!
Quickly, tell me who!
Well, Boss, the black magic shaman is…
Can you talk or not?
Yes, I can.
The black magic shaman is…
You two, weren't you with him earlier?
Yes, Boss.
So who is the shaman?
-I don't know, Boss.
-I don't know either.
Did you see anyone enter Suzzanna's house?
-No.
-No, Boss.
One is stuttering,
and the other two don't know anything.
It's useless for me
to talk to stupid people like you.
Hey!
Do you want to get us killed?
Huh? We can get killed?
We might if this keeps happening.
Why would you report to the boss
without knowing who the shaman is?
I actually know. I saw it.
That's why I want to talk to the boss.
But it couldn't come out.
Can't you just write
the name of the shaman?
Here, write it down.
I can't read or write.
Wow, you're stuttering and illiterate.
Can you read and write?
-I can't.
-Geez.
I'm having a hard
time listening to you two.
How are we supposed to improve,
if the quality of our human resources
is this low?
What's wrong with them?
I just wanted to tell them
that the black magic shaman is Suzzanna.
Huh, I said it?
I think she put a spell on me.
Scattered from the world,
everything lies in ruin.
Purged, without a trace.
Not bad.
You spent months away from this village.
And mastered
witchcraft before coming home.
Too bad.
You think too highly of yourself.
You think you can beat everyone.
I have never studied witchcraft.
But just so you know,
from Ponorogo,
up to Banyuwangi,
I know many shamans.
And every one gave me something
to protect myself.
It's okay.
Let's just forget the past.
You should focus
on having a better future.
By accepting my proposal.
I'm still waiting
for you to complete
the requirements I told you.
I've helped finish off two men.
There is one more
left, who is still alive.
Tomorrow morning, take me to Ponorogo.
I want to visit Mbah Kodrat.
You realize,
what could happen if I put
a soul-split spell on your future wife?
-I understand.
-Won't you be disappointed?
That you're marrying a completely
different woman?
No, Mbah.
It's better that way.
Instead of having her recognize me,
and hate me all my life.
Do you know where you are?
What's your name?
If you don't know what your name is,
I will give you the name Suzzanna.
You should eat.
You haven't eaten since yesterday.
Why did you come back here?
Because I still want to find my father.
What is your mother's name?
Astuti.
Here's the photo.
But I don't have a photo of my father.
She said my father was a sailor.
And he had an accident
when she gave birth to me.
Your father lied.
He was not a sailor.
His name is not Kasman either.
He faked his name
and claimed to be a sailor,
to find an excuse to
leave your mother often.
Because he had lovers everywhere.
After that, your father left this village,
and never came back again.
Do you know where my father is?
I'll tell you where your father is, only
after you answer my questions honestly.
God willing, I will answer honestly, sir.
What is your real purpose
in coming to Karang Setan?
-To look for my father.
-Liar.
-You came here for Suzzanna, didn't you?
-No.
What is your relationship with her?
Why do you feel the need to come here?
Do you love her?
Why are you asking about
my relationship with Suzzanna?
Because soon she will marry me.
And I have to make sure
no one else has any objections.
Suzzanna will not marry you.
Unless you force her.
As long as I am alive,
I will make sure that will never happen.
We shall see.
Suzzanna.
Put down the broom. We'll talk inside.
Suzzanna?
Who are you?
Just wait inside. Okay?
What did you do to her?
Which shaman did you ask
to corrupt her mind?
None of your business.
Soon, she will be my wife.
Enough.
Let's just finish him off, Boss.
No. Give him supplies
to go home to Kalinegoro.
Take him.
Who are you?
You're an officer, right?
What are you doing peeking into
the bridal chamber like this?
Do you want to be beaten up by the chief?
No! I don't mean to harm Suzzanna.
-I swear!
-If you don't mean any harm,
why are you acting like a thief?
And what are you doing here? Perhaps…
-Are you a thief calling me a thief?
-I came here to help Suzzanna.
Me too!
-Can you help me?
-Yes.
VILLAGE TRANSPORTATION
-Come on, pick her up.
-Come on.
Watch her head.
Watch it.
Pull her up.
-So you guys have repented?
-Whatever, shut up.
WELCOME TO KARANG SETAN VILLAGE
Auntie?
Suzzanna?
Sorry, Auntie. I had to come back.
For Suzzanna's sake.
Someone made her lose her memory.
The soul-split spell.
Her body is strong enough
not to drive her crazy.
But the treatment you taught me…
I haven't mastered it yet.
You don't need to
learn strange things like me.
Come on. Come inside.
Come.
Come on, dear.
Come on.
If you don't mind,
I'll leave Suzzanna here for now.
I have something to do in Karang Setan.
With pleasure, my boy.
Be careful, okay?
Forgive me, will you?
If you still want to stay here,
I won't kick you out.
My house is your house too.
Who are you?
Who the hell are you?
Do you want to know what dying feels like?
Feel it
before you die.
Tell me.
Who told you to bother Suzzanna?
It's none of your business!
It sure is.
Whoever decides
to bother Suzzanna
will be dealing with me.
Oh, no.
Now… It's time for you to die.
Die, Gayatri. Die!
Your time here is over.
Hey!
I know your soul is lodged in your throat.
Once I bind you,
you will become my puppet.
Face the full moon's light,
old shaman!
Tohir.
How did it go?
-I can't find her.
-You can't?
Hey, where's Kliwon?
Getting dolled up. Wait, what?
You think Kliwon is
the one getting married?
-Sorry, Boss, I mean…
-Has Suzzanna finished her makeup?
I've been looking, Boss
I'm asking about Suzzanna.
It has nothing to do with Kliwon.
I'm also answering about Suzzanna.
Not about Kliwon.
Why did you say you're looking?
Is she missing?
If she wasn't,
I wouldn't be looking for her.
-Do you know where Suzzanna is?
-No, Boss.
Kawi! Where's Suzzanna?
It seems like he wants to kill your soul.
Without damaging your body.
Let me learn what it takes
to get rid of his protection, Ma'am.
His defense is too strong for me to fight.
About his protection,
let me handle it.
But to attack him,
there is actually one thing
which I haven't taught
because it's too dangerous.
It is called…
the bamboo-bundle spell.
Its power is equal to the death-hex,
but it won’t strike only Bisman.
All of his descendants
will perish as well.
Bisman has no descendants, Ma'am.
There will be no
victims other than himself.
I will teach it to you
but only for one attack.
And this cannot be undone.
If you try to undo it,
its destructive power will return
to hit the sender.
To hit you.
Listen, everyone.
This is Boss Bisman's order.
All of you
must work together
to look for Suzzanna until you find her.
If Suzzanna is still not found by sunset,
you have to bear the consequences.
Boss Bisman will only give you time
until tomorrow night
for you to pay off your debts.
What? What?
If you don't agree, come up here!
Don't grumble behind my back.
Why so silent?
Get out of here. Scatter!
Hurry up and find Suzzanna!
That's not their job.
Huh?
Who said that?
I'm not from here.
But I know this is just your trick
to make them pay their debts.
Don't mess around
with Boss Bisman's orders.
Even the stupidest person in this village
knows that your order is unreasonable.
Pass these around.
If Suzzanna really disappeared,
she could have run to Ngawi,
Jombang, Kediri,
so you're saying that we should
search all the villages?
All the towns? Do you all
want to look for Suzzanna everywhere?
-No!
-No, no!
-Shut up!
-No!
Whether this concerns Suzzanna or not,
a debt is a debt.
Who put them in debt?
You must know.
Five years ago,
Boss Bisman deliberately spread pests,
and destroyed all the rice fields
in this village.
Tens of hectares in number.
Then after the crop failed, what happened?
They were all forced to borrow money
from Boss Bisman.
If they wanted to pay their debts,
they mortgaged their rice fields.
Become laborers on their own rice fields
which are now owned by Boss Bisman, right?
That's right, that's right!
I experienced it myself.
This is colonization.
Oppression.
Pursuing wealth to gain power.
Using power to make yourself richer
by causing misery to others.
Do you want to keep being oppressed?
No!
Do you want to keep being wronged?
-No.
-No!
This is slander. Beat him up. Get him!
We have to get the cash safe
in the café cupboard.
Bisman! Where are you?
Come on, Boss.
Bisman is getting away!
Bisman! Don't run away!
Bisman!
Let's go!
Hey, lock all the doors!
Come on, guys! Come on!
The key is at home.
Attack, don't be afraid!
Here, Boss.
Wait here, Boss.
Take that!
Bisman!
I humbly ask for your help.
Boss…
Help me.
Help.
Wait.
Help…
SATRIYO SON OF WARYONO
SUTINI, DAUGHTER OF PRAYITNO
Suzzanna.
I feel worthless.
-Seeing my parents' grave.
-Suzzanna.
You only need to do one thing.
Abandon your mystical powers.
I can help you.
I know someone in Trenggalek
who can help you, and he can heal you.
It's not that easy.
It all depends on your intentions,
Suzzanna.
But will Allah forgive my sins?
Allah is Most Forgiving.
You just have to believe.
Thank you.
For always helping me.
Not just once, but twice.
Three times.
You forgot the motorbike.
Alright then.
I've been looking around for you.
Turns out you're here.
What is it?
Earlier the police came to the office
-with a letter for you, Pramuja.
-Yes.
They said this was found
in the living room of Bisman's house.
For me?
Yes.
Carry on then.
Hope you get married. Ow!
Get married soon.
Gosh.
Did your father…
know Bisman?
Bisman once told me that
he knew my father.
It's my mother's picture.
Why did Bisman have
a photo of your mother?
Pramuja.
This is the first time I've felt
what happiness is like.
That is after knowing
that I have a very good son.
So unlike his father.
You can be embarrassed
to have a father like me.
But I am proud to have a son like you.
It is called the bamboo-bundle spell.
Its power is equal to the death-hex,
but it won’t strike only Bisman.
All of his descendants
will perish as well.
If you try to undo it,
its destructive power will return
to hit the sender.
To hit you.
I’m sorry I couldn’t be
a good father to you.
Even though it’s impossible
to erase the mistakes I’ve made,
I have decided
to leave all of my wealth to you.
I hope you can find it in your heart
to forgive me.
Suzzanna.
Suzzanna?
Suzzanna!
Suzzanna! Open up!
What's wrong with you? Open the door!
Let me bear all the consequences
of my actions, Pramuja.
I cast the witchcraft not only to Bisman,
but also, to all his descendants.
Oh, God.
You won't end up like Bisman
because I've already cancelled the attack.
It will hit me back.
No, don't. Don't do this.
No, Suzzanna. Don't do this.
There must be another way.
You can cancel all of this by repenting.
It's not that easy, Pramuja.
I've gone too far
down the wrong path.
The unforgiving path of polytheism.
Full of sin.
Forgiveness belongs to Allah.
It's not up to us to decide.
I beg you to ask forgiveness from Allah.
Ask Allah for help
while you still have the chance.
The doors of heaven are no longer open
for me, Pramuja.
The doors of heaven are locked for me.
But I'm happy.
Seeing Karang Setan free from oppression.
Like my father's wish.
Every change
requires sacrifice.
Suzzanna, don't. Suzzanna!
Suzzanna?
Oh…
Oh, God…
Oh, God, please forgive her.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
respected residents of Karang Setan.
There are several things
I would like to convey to you.
I, Pramuja,
am the son of Boss…
I am the son of Bisman.
Therefore, I inherited his wealth.
The wealth that he had obtained so far
in ways that defy religious rules,
and violate state regulations.
I will return them completely
to all of you, ladies and gentlemen.
Oh, thank God.
All of your debt to Bisman
will be considered paid.
Thank God.
The rice fields that were forcibly seized,
from all of you
shall be returned to you completely.
KARANG NIRWONO MARKET - BANYUWANGI
KARANG NIRWONO VILLAGE HEAD OFFICE
SUZZANNA DAUGHTER OF SATRIYO